

With over three years of experience in developing innovative IoT, data and digitalization solutions, I have

extensive know-how. I have mastered waterfall model, agile methods and the DevOps process to successfully implement projects. I attach great importance to developing together

with the company, using new technologies and implementing innovative digitalization products.

REQUIREMENT ENGINEERING

AGILE PROJECTMANAGEMENT

**CLASSIC PROJECTMANAGEMENT** 

ANALYTICAL THINKING

**STATISTICS** 

**DATA SCIENCE** 

**DATA ANALYSIS** 

Soft Skills

About Me

# Michael Bieri

Grotweg 23
2543 Lengnau BE
+41 77 413 08 39
michael.bieri@hotmail.com
13.03.1992







## Work Experience

07/2024 - 10/2024	Career transition Relocation, travel and continuing education
03/2021 - 06/2024	Product Engineer Electronics LAUFEN Bathrooms AG, Laufen
	Development and management of soft- and hardware projects with focus on requirement engineering
09/2018 - 02/2021	<b>Junior Project Manager</b> Amstein + Walthert Basel AG, Basel
	Engineering in building technology/automation
07/2018 - 09/2018	Internship Environmental Engineer Kappeler Infra Consult AG, Laufen
11/2013 - 07/2014	Internship Workshop and Engineering F. Hoffmann-La-Roche AG, Basel
11/2010 - 05/2011	Internship Trust TVR Treuhand GmbH, Basel
09/2009 - 10/2009	Internship Bank WIR Bank Genossenschaft, Basel



#### Education

02/2024 - 08/2024	<b>CAS Data Science Fundamentals</b> Swiss Distance University of Applied Sciences FFHS
09/2019 - 04/2022	MAS Automation Management University of Applied Sciences Northwestern Switzerland FHNW
09/2014 - 05/2018	BSc Energy- and Environment Technology University of Applied Sciences Northwestern Switzerland FHNW
08/2011 - 08/2012	Technical High School Diploma Vocational training center BL, Liestal
08/2007 - 08/2010	Business Diploma Business school kvBL, Reinach BL

### Certificates

- CPRE Foundation Level
- Professional Scrum Master II
- Databricks Certified Data Engineer Associate
- Microsoft Fundamentals in Azure, Power Platform, MS365



#### Languages

French

German	Mother tongue
English	C1

B2